<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi, I am Chirag on Chirag Chopra</title>
    <link>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi, I am Chirag on Chirag Chopra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:00:59 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 4 : Bank Customer Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Bank-Customer-Segmentation Bank Customer Segmentation with kmeans, PCA and Encoder decoder.
 1. Overview : a. Goal :  It&amp;rsquo;s crucial for marketers to know customer and their needs To design targeted marketing campaign tailored for specific needs. For that they need to perform accurate customer segmentation.  b. Challenges Faced :  Collection of data from twitter through twitter API Structuring and making sense of unstructured and noisy text data. Data cleaning and preprocessing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3 : Stocks-Sentiment-Analysis-NLP-LSTM</title>
      <link>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Stocks-Sentiment-Analysis-NLP-LSTM Stocks Sentiment Analysis NLP LSTM
 1. Overview Goal  Humungous data on social media about a stock which is impossible to go through and make decisions. Leverage technology to gain interesting insights and make better investment decisions.  Impact  Based on the signals of the model investors can make confident and well informed decisions. Time saved by 95% by leveraging technology. Avoid decision fatigue and analysis paralysis.  Challenges Faced  Collection of data from twitter through twitter API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 : Stock-Price-Prediction</title>
      <link>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Stock-Price-Prediction  In this project, I trained a Ridge regression model and deep neural network model to predict future stock prices. The AI model will be trained using historical stock price data along with volume of transactions.   1. Overview : a. Goal :  Based on volume and price data , can we predict stock prices? Why? Because while investing other peoples money we need to be really careful and we need real data to support our decisions rather than intuition  b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1 : Asset_allocation</title>
      <link>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Stocks-Data-Analysis-and-Visualization-in-Python Stocks Data Analysis and Visualization in Python
 1. Overview: a. Goal:  Created a funtion to perform portfolio analysis by calculating return, risk and Sharpe ratio The main problem was the huge manual effort required and the visualization of the results Reduced analysis time by 20%  b. Challenges Faced:  Wrangling data of different stocks and combining them into a single dataframee. Missing values. Plotting QQ plot for stock modelling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chiggy1997.github.io/data_science_portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these Social Media Platforms
   Platform      LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/chirag-chopra/   Gmail: chiragchopra2012@gmail.com    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
